Welcome to our training on the Brand Analytics Demographics Report.
Brands enrolled in Amazon Brand Registry enjoy access to a suite of additional selling benefits
including the Brand Analytics tool in Seller Central.
In this video, we'll review the features and functionality of one of the reports you'll find in
Brand Analytics, Demographics.
This report provides brands with a breakdown of sales for their products using various customer
categories.
It can help them understand who is buying their products, and they can use it to define advertising
strategies.
You can access the Demographics report and others in the Brand Analytics tool if you're a seller
internal to a brand enrolled in Brand Registry.
Simply select Brands in the main menu in Seller Central, then click Brand Analytics, or click All
Brand Benefits, then locate the Brand Analytics card.
For more information about accessing Brand Analytics and other Brand Registry tools, see our modules
in Seller University about requesting or managing access to Brand Selling benefits.
After accessing the Brand Analytics tool, you can select Demographics from the list of reports at
the top of the screen.
The report provides a breakdown of sales for your brand's products across five customer categories,
age, income, education, gender, and marital status.
The data shown is reflective of primary customer account holders, and includes sales of your brand's
products across all sellers.
To help ensure customer privacy, we only surface brands and customer categories associated with
at least 100 unique customers.
In each section of the report, a customer category is divided into segments.
For example, age is divided into six segments in the Demographics report, starting with 18 to 24-
year-olds and ending with those 65 and older.
For each segment, you'll see the total number of unique customers, as well as a percentage of total,
that's the number of unique customers in the segment divided by the number of unique customers in
the entire category.
You'll also see a percentage of total change versus prior period for each segment, which is the
difference in the number of unique customers compared to the previous reporting period.
For example, if in the current week your brand had 300 customers who were 18 to 24-years-old and
1,000 total customers, the percentage of total for the segment would be 30%.
If in the previous week your brand had 150 customers who were 18 to 24-years-old, the percentage
of total change versus prior period would be 100% because the number of customers in the segment
had doubled from one week to the next.
In the second set of rows in the Demographics report, you'll see similar metrics for the number
of units sold.
For example, in the current week, 18 to 24-year-olds purchased 600 units associated with your brand
and 3,000 units were purchased overall.
In this scenario, the percentage of total for the segment would be 20%.
If in the previous week 300 units were purchased by 18 to 24-year-olds, the percent of total change
versus prior period would be 100% because the number of units purchased doubled.
When you first access the Demographics report, it'll be defaulted to show sales across all product
categories and brands for the previous week.
You can use the first two drop-down menus at the top to view a specific time period.
Keep in mind that data is generally available in brand analytics within three days and that for
the Demographics report, month-end data is available within four days and quarter-end data is available
within one week.
You can use the remaining drop-down menus to select a specific brand or category.
After making selections, click the Apply button to refresh the report.
If you'd like to add or remove columns on the Demographics report, click Customize Columns on the
right-hand side, then check or uncheck boxes in the popup.
Click the Save button to return to the updated report.
To download a copy of the report, click the Generate Download button.
Then, in the popup, select either Simple View to download the report you see on screen or select
Comprehensive View to download the report with all relevant columns.
Click the Generate Download button to start your download, which you can monitor by accessing the
Download Manager.
Finally, if you want more information about how a specific metric is calculated, click Metrics Glossary
to see a set of comprehensive definitions.
On the Metrics Glossary page, you can expand each section to see additional details.
We encourage brands to use all the features and functionality of the Demographics report to gain
insights into their performance in the Amazon Store.
Use it to help make strategic decisions about your brand catalog.
If you notice your products are being purchased by certain demographic segments, you can explore
other products popular with those segments.
Or you can use the report to develop advertising campaigns focused on one or more customer categories.
This concludes our overview of the Demographics report.
If you'd like step-by-step instructions for other brand analytics reports, see our series of modules
in Seller University.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon Store!